Chapter 25. Postcript.
In behalf of the dignity of whailing, I would fain advance not but substantiated
facts. But after embattling his facts, an advocate who should wholly suppress a
not unreasonable surmise, which might tell eloquently upon his case, such an
advocate, would he not be blameworthy?
It is well known that at the coronation of kings and queens, even modern ones, a
certain curious process of seasoning them for their functions has gone
through. There is a salt seller of state, so-called, and there may be a
caster of state. How they use the salt precisely, who knows? Certain I am,
however, that a king's head is solemnly oiled at his coronation, even as a head
of salad. Can it be, though, that they anoint it with a view of making his
interior run well, as they anoint machinery? Much might be ruminated here
concerning the essential dignity of this regal process, because in common life we
esteem but meanly and contemptably a fellow who anoints his hair and palpably
smells of that anointing. In truth, a mature man who uses hair oil, unless
medically that man has probably got a quaggy spot in him somewhere, as a
general rule, he can't amount to much in his totality.
But the only thing to be considered here is this. What kind of oil is used at
coronation? Certainly, it cannot be olive oil or macasser oil, nor castor
oil, nor bears oil, nor train oil, nor cod liver oil. What then can it possibly
be but sperm oil in its unmanufactured, unpolluted state? The sweetest of all
oils. Think of that, ye loyal Britain.
We whaleman supply your kings and queens with coronation stuff.